When building a complex application using an LLM,
当使用LLM构建复杂应用程序时，
one of the important but sometimes tricky steps is
一个重要但有时有点棘手的步骤是
how do you evaluate how well your application is doing?
如何评估应用程序的表现？
Is it meeting some accuracy criteria?
它是否达到了某种验收标准？
And also, if you decide to change your implementation,
此外，如果你决定换一种实现方式，
maybe swap in a different LLM
可能换到不同的LLM，
or change the strategy of how you use a vector database or something else to retrieve channels,
或者更改如何使用向量数据库的策
略，或者使用其他方式检索数据，
How do you know if you're making it better or worse?
你要怎么样知道结果是比以
前更好了？还是更糟糕了？
In this video, Harrison will dive into some frameworks to how to think about evaluating a LLM based application,
在这个视频中，Harrison将深入探讨一些框
架，以思考如何评估基于LLM的应用程序，
as well as some tools that help you do that.
同时会介绍一些帮助你评估的工具。
These applications are really chains and sequences of a lot of different steps.
这些应用实际上是许多不同步骤的链和序列。
And so honestly, part of the first thing that you should do is
我们的首要任务是
just understand what exactly is going in and coming out of each step.
了解每个步骤的输入和输出到底是什么。
And so some of the tools can really just be thought of as visualizers or debuggers in that thing.
因此，我们会用到一些可视化工具和调试工具。
But it's often really useful to get a more holistic picture on a lot of different data points of how the model is doing.
使用大量不同的数据集来测试模型，这
有助于我们全面了解模型的表现。
And one way to do that is by looking at things by eye.
观察事物的一种方法是用肉眼看。
But there's also this really cool idea of using language models themselves and chains themselves to evaluate other language models and other chains and other applications.
但还有一个非常酷的想法，就是使
用语言模型和链来评估其他语言模
型、其他链和其他应用程序。
And we'll dive a bunch into that as well.
我们也会深入探讨这个想法。
So lots of cool topics,
这个视频中有很多有趣的话题，
and I find that with a lot of development shifting towards prompting-based development, developing applications using LLMs,
我发现随着越来越多的开发转向基于
Prompt的开发，使用LLM开发应用程序，
this whole workflow evaluation process is being rethought.
整个工作流程、评估过程正在被重新思考。
So lots of exciting concepts in this video.
这个视频里有很多激动人心的概念。
Let's dive in.
让我们开始吧。
All right, so let's get set up with evaluation.
好的，让我们开始设置评估所需要的环境。
First, we need to have the chain or the application that we're going to evaluate in the first place.
首先，我们需要有一个链或应
用程序，以便进行评估。
And we're going to use the document question answering chain from the previous lesson.
我们将使用上一课的文档问答链。
So we're going to import everything we need.
所以我们要导入所需的相关库。
We're going to load the same data that we were using.
我们将加载上一课中使用过的相同数据。
We're going to create that index with one line.
我们将用一行代码创建索引。
And then we're going to create the retrieval QA chain by specifying the language model, the chain type, the retriever, and then the verbosity that we're going to print out.
然后，我们将通过指定语言模型、链类型、检
索器以及verbosity（要打印日志的详细程
度）这些参数来创建RetrievalQA链。
So we've got this application.
现在我们有了这个应用程序。
And the first thing we need to do is
我们需要做的第一件事就是
And so there's a few different methods that we're going to cover for doing this.
我将介绍几种不同的方法来实现这个目标。
The first is the most simple,
第一个方法最简单，
which is basically we're going to come up with data points that we think are good examples ourselves.
就是自己想出一些好的示例数据集。
and then example ground truth answers that we can later use to evaluate.
然后提供可以用于评估的标准答案。
So if we look at a few of the documents here,
让我们看一下这里的几份文档，
It looks like the first one, there's this pullover set.
看起来第一个文档是关于一套连帽衫的。
There's this in the second one, there's this jacket as a bunch of details about all of them.
第二个文档是关于一件夹克
的，都有很多详细信息。
And from these details, we can create some example query and answer pairs.
从这些详细信息中，我们可以创
建若干组示例问题和答案。
So the first one, we can ask a simple, "Does the Cozy Comfort Pullover Set have side pockets?"
第一个问题，我们可以简单地问：“舒
适保暖连帽衫套装有侧口袋吗？”
And we can see by looking above that it does, in fact, have some side pockets in it.
我们可以通过上面看到，它确实有侧口袋。
And then for the second one, we can see that this Jacket is from a certain collection, the DownTek collection.
对于第二个，我们可以看到这件夹
克来自某个系列，DownTek系列。
And so we can ask the question, "What collection is this jacket from?"
所以我们可以问这个问题："
这件夹克来自哪个系列？"
And have the answer be, "The DownTek collection".
答案是："DownTek系列"。
And so here we've created two examples.
所以在这里我们创建了两组问答示例。
But this doesn't really scale that well.
但是，这种方式并不易于扩展。
It takes a bit of time to look through each example and figure out what's going on.
需要花费一些时间来查看每个
示例，弄清楚发生了什么。
And one of the really cool ways that we think we can automate it is with language models themselves.
借助语言模型来自动化这个过
程是一种非常酷的方式。
So we have a chain in LangChain that can do exactly that.
在LangChain中有一个链可以做到这一点。
So we can import the QAGenerationChain
我们可以导入QAGenerationChain
and this will take in documents and it will create a question answer pair from each document.
它可以读取文档并从每个文档
中生成一组问题和答案。
It'll do this using a language model itself.
它将借助语言模型来实现。
So we need to create this chain by passing in the ChatOpenAI language model.
因此，我们需要通过传入
ChatOpenAI语言模型来创建这个
链。
And then from there, we can create a bunch of examples.
然后我们可以用它创建很
多组问题和答案示例。
And so we're going to use the apply_and_parse method, because this is applying an output parser to the result.
我们将使用apply_and_parse方法，
应用解析器来解析输出的结果。
Because we want to get back a dictionary that has the query and answer pair, not just a single string.
因为我们想要得到一系列包含一组问题和答
案的字典对象，而不是一个文本字符串。
we can see a query and we can see an answer.
我们可以看到一个问题和一个答案。
And let's check the document that this is a question and answer for.
让我们检查一下这是哪个文档的问题和答案。
And we can see that it's asking what the weight of this is.
我们可以看到它在问这个的重量是多少。
We can see that it's taking the weight from here.
我们可以看到它是从这里获取重量的。
And look at that.
看看这个，
We just generated a bunch of question answer pairs.
我们刚刚生成了很多组问题和答案，
We didn't have to write it all ourselves.
不需要去一个个手动生成。
Saves us a bunch of time and we can do more exciting things.
这样可以帮我们节省很多时间，可
以去做更多其他有意思的事情。
And so now let's go ahead and add these examples into the examples that we already created.
现在让我们把这些示例加入到
我们已经创建的示例中。
So we got these examples now, but how exactly do we evaluate what's going on?
现在我们有了这些示例数据，但
是我们如何评估效果如何？
The first thing we want to do is just run an example through the chain and take a look at the output it produces.
首先，我们要做的就是将其中某个示例传
入链并运行，然后观察它输出的结果。
So here we pass in a query and we get back.
这里我们输入一个问题，然后得到返回结果。
but this is a little bit limiting in terms of what we can see that's actually happening inside the chain.
但我们无法观察到链的内部到底发生了什么！
What is the actual prompt that's going into the language model?
例如传给语言模型中的Prompt是什么？
If this were a more complex chain with multiple steps in it, what are the intermediate results?
如果这是一个包含多个步骤的复杂链
，那么每一步的中间结果是什么？
It's oftentimes not enough to just look at the final answer to understand
仅仅观察最终答案通常不足以理解
what is or could be going wrong in the chain.
链中哪里出错或可能出错。
And to help with that, we have a fun little util in LangChain called LangChain debug.
为了解决这个问题，LangChain中提供了一个有
意思的小工具，叫做“langchain debug”。
And so if we set "langchain.debug" equals "True",
如果我们把 "langchain.
debug" 设为 "True",
and we now rerun the same example as above,
然后把之前的示例再运行一遍，
we can see that it starts printing out a lot more information.
就可以看到它输出了更多的信息。
And so if we look at what exactly it's printing out,
如果我们看看它到底输出了什么，
we can see that it's diving down first into the RetrievalQA chain.
我们可以看到它首先调用了RetrievalQA链，
And then it's going down into a StuffDocumentsChain.
然后它又调用了StuffDocumentsChain。
And so as mentioned, we were using the "stuff" method.
上一节课讲到过，我们使用了 "stuff" 方法。
So we can see the original question is right there.
可以看到原始问题，
And now we're passing in this context.
传入的上下文，
And we can see that this context is created from a bunch of the different documents that we've retrieved.
可以看到这个上下文是根据问题
检索到的几个文档块内容。
And so when doing question answering,
在做问答时，
oftentimes when a wrong result is returned, it's not necessarily the language model itself that's messing up.
往往当返回错误的结果时，不一
定是语言模型本身出了问题。
It's actually the retrieval step that's messing up.
实际上，可能是在检索的步骤出了问题。
And so taking a really close look at what exactly the question is
仔细查看问题的确切内容
and what exactly the context is can help debug what's going wrong.
和上下文的确切内容可以帮
助调试，找出问题在哪。
We can then step down one more level and see exactly what is entering the language model, ChatOpenAI, itself.
我们可以再深入一层，看看究竟传入语言模
型（ChatOpenAI）的Prompt究竟是什么。
And so here we can see the full prompt that's passed in.
这里我们可以看到传入语
言模型的完整Prompt：
So we've got a system message.
有一个系统消息。
We've got the description of the prompt that's used.
有一个对Prompt的描述。
And so this is the prompt that the question answering chain is using under the hood,
这就是问答链在底层使用的Prompt，
which we actually haven't even looked at until now.
我们直到现在才看到。
And so we can see the prompt printing out, use the following pieces of context to answer the user's question.
我们可以看到Prompt输出：“使用以下
上下文信息来回答用户的问题，
If you don't know the answer, just say that you don't know.
如果你不知道答案，就说不知道，
Don't try to make up an answer.
不要试图编造答案。”
And then we see a bunch of the context as inserted before.
然后我们看到之前插入的一堆上下文。
And then we see a human question, which is the question that we asked it.
接着我们看到一个人类提出的问
题，这就是我们问它的问题。
We can also see a lot more information about the actual return type.
我们还可以看到更多语言
模型返回的结果信息。
So rather than just a string, we get back a bunch of information like the token usage,
所以不仅仅是一个字符串，我们还得到
了诸如Token使用量这样的信息，
so the prompt tokens, the completion tokens, total tokens, and the model name.
比如Prompt消耗了多少Token、返回的结果消耗
了多少Token、总共消耗的Token数和模型名称。
And this can be really useful to track the tokens that you're using in your chains or calls to language models over time
这些信息对于跟踪在链或调用语言模
型中使用了多少Token非常有用，
and keep track of the total number of tokens, which corresponds very closely to the total cost.
根据消耗的Token数和模型，可
以算出来花费了多少成本。
And because this is a relatively simple chain,
因为这是一个相对简单的链，
we can now see that the final response,
我们现在可以看到最后的返回结果：
"The Cozy Comfort Pullover Set, Stripe, does have side pockets.",
“舒适保暖连帽衫套装，条纹款，有侧口袋。”，
is getting bubbled up through the chains and getting returned to the user.
通过链传递并返回给用户。
So we've just walked through how to look at and debug
我们刚刚讲解了如何查看和调试
what's going on with a single input to this chain.
这个链中单个输入的情况。
But what about all the examples we created?
但是如何输入我们前面创建的所有示例呢？
How are we going to evaluate those?
我们该如何评估它们呢？
then look at the outputs and try to figure out what's going on, whether it's correct, incorrect, partially correct.
然后观察输出，搞清楚发生了什么
，是否正确、错误或部分正确。
Similar to creating the examples, that starts to get a little bit tedious over time.
与创建示例数据类似，手动操作的方法
随着时间的推移会变得有些繁琐。
And so let's go back to our favorite solution.
所以让我们回到大家最喜欢的解决方案。
Can we ask a language model to do it?
能让语言模型来完成吗？
First, we need to create predictions for all the examples.
首先，我们需要为所有示例生成实际答案。
Before doing that,
在此之前，
I'm actually going to turn off the debug mode in order to just not print everything out onto the screen,
我实际上要关闭调试模式，以
免把所有内容都打印出来，
and then I'm going to create predictions for all the different examples.
然后我将为所有不同的示例生成实际答案。
And so I think we had seven examples total,
我想我们总共有七个示例，
and so we're going to loop through this chain seven times, getting a prediction for each one.
我们将循环七次，为每个示
例生成一个实际答案。
Now that we've got these examples, we can think about evaluating them.
现在我们有了这些示例，可以考虑评估它们。
So we're going to import the QA, question answering, eval chain.
我们将导入QAEvalChain。
We are going to create this chain with a language model,
我们将用语言模型创建这个链，
because again, we're going to be using a language model to help do the evaluation.
因为我们将使用语言模型来帮助评估。
And then we're going to call evaluate on this chain.
然后我们将在这个链上调用"evaluate"方法。
We're going to pass in examples and predictions,
并传入示例列表和实际答案列表，
we're going to loop through them.
我们将遍历它们。
We're going to print out the question.
我们要打印出问题。
And again, this was generated by a language model.
再次说明，这是由语言模型生成的。
And so it could generate a ground truth answer.
所以它生成的标准答案是可靠的。
We're going to print out the predicted answer.
我们要打印出实际答案。
And this is generated by a language model when it's doing the QA chain,
这是在语言模型和问答链生成的，
when it's doing the retrieval with the embeddings in the vector databases, passing that into a language model,
先对问题生成Embedding，然后去向
量数据库检索相似文档，再将检索
出来的文档传递给语言模型，
and then trying to guess the predicted answer.
然后语言模型生成实际答案。
And then we're also going to print it out the grade.
我们还会打印出评分。
And again, this is also generated by a language model
再次强调，这也是由语言模型生成的
when it's asking the eval chain to grade what's going on and whether it's correct or incorrect.
评估链对标准答案和实际答案进行
对比，判断对错，得出一个评分。
And so when we loop through all these examples and print them out,
所以当我们遍历所有这些示例并打印它们时，
we can see those in detail for each example.
可以详细查看每个示例。
And looks like here it got everything correct.
看起来每一个示例都做对了。
This is a relatively simple retrieval problem, so that is reassuring.
这是一个相对简单的检索问题，
所以这结果还是靠得住的。
So let's look at the first example.
那我们来看第一个示例。
The question here is, "Does the Cozy Comfort Pullover Set have side pockets?"
这里的问题是：“舒适保暖套装有侧面口袋吗？”
The real answer, and we created this, is "Yes".
我们创建的标准答案是：“是的”。
The predicted answer, which the language model produced, was,
语言模型生成的实际答案是：
"The Cozy Comfort Pullover Set, Stripe does have side pockets".
“舒适保暖套装，条纹款确实有侧面口袋。”
And so we can understand that this is a correct answer.
所以我们可以认为这个答案是正确的。
And actually the language model does as well and it creates it correct.
实际上，语言模型也知道，并
且它把它标记为正确。
But let's think about why we actually need to use the language model in the first place.
但让我们想想为什么我们需要使用语言模型。
These two strings are actually nothing alike.
因为这两个字符串实际上一点都不像。
They're very different.
它们非常不同。
One's really short, one's really long.
一个很短，一个很长。
I don't even think "Yes" doesn't appear anywhere in this string.
“是的”这个词在这个长字符串里都没有出现。
So if we were to try to do some string matching or exact matching or even some regexes here,
所以如果我们试图进行字符串匹配、
精确匹配或者使用正则表达式，
it wouldn't know what to do.
是无法对两个字符串进行比较的。
They're not the same thing.
它们不是同一回事。
And that shows off the importance of using the language model to do evaluation here.
这就突显了在这里使用语言
模型进行评估的重要性。
You've got these answers.
你有这些答案，
which are arbitrary strings.
它们可能是任意的字符串。
There's no single one-truth string that is the best possible answer.
答案不是唯一的，
There's many different variants.
有很多不同的变体。
And as long as they have the same semantic meaning,
只要它们意思相同，
they should be graded as being similar.
它们就应该被看做是相似的。
And that's what a language model helps with, as opposed to just doing exact matching.
这就是语言模型的作用，而
不仅仅是进行精确匹配。
This difficulty in comparing strings is what makes evaluation of language models so hard in the first place.
之所以对语言模型的评估如此困难，
就是因为很难对字符串进行比较。
We're using them for these really open-ended tasks where they're asked to generate text.
我们将语言模型用于这些非常开
放的任务，让它们生成文本。
And so a lot of the evaluation metrics that did exist up to this point just aren't good enough.
目前为止很多现存的评估指标都不够好。
and we're having to invent new ones and invent new heuristics for doing so.
我们不得不发明新的指标和新的启发式方法。
And the most interesting and most popular of those heuristics at the moment is actually
目前最有趣和最受欢迎的启发式方法实际上是
using a language model to do the evaluation.
使用语言模型进行评估。
This finishes the evaluation lesson, but one last thing I want to show you is the LangChain evaluation platform.
这节关于评估的课程到此就结束了，但我还想
给你们展示一下LangChain的评估平台。
This is a way to do everything that we just did in the notebook, but persist it and show it in a UI.
借助评估平台可以在Notebook中完
成我们刚做的所有事情，并且可以在
UI中显示，并对数据持久化。
And so let's check it out.
那么让我们看看。
Here, we can see that we have a session.
在这里，可以看到有一个会话。
We called it "deeplearningai".
我们称之为"deeplearningai"。
And we can see here that we've actually persisted all the runs that we ran in the notebook.
可以看到实际上已经保存了我们在
Notebook中运行的所有记录。
And so this is a good way to track the inputs and outputs at a high level,
这是一个跟踪输入和输出的好方法，
but it's also a really good way to see what exactly is going on underneath.
也是一个查看底层究竟发生了什么的好方法。
So this is the same information that was printed out in the notebook when we turned on debug mode,
这与我们在Notebook中打开调试
模式时打印出的信息相同，
but it's just visualized in a UI in a little bit of a nicer way.
但它在UI中以更好的方式呈现。
And so we can see the inputs to the chain and the outputs to the chain at each step.
我们可以看到链的输入和
每个步骤中链的输出。
and see more and more information about what is actually getting passed in.
了解更多实际传入的信息。
And so if we go all the way down to the bottom,
如果我们一直到最底层，
we can now see what's getting passed exactly to the chat model.
可以看到究竟向聊天模型传入了什么内容。
We've got the system message here.
这里有系统消息。
We've got the human question here.
这里有人类的问题。
We've got the response from the Chat Model here.
这里有来自聊天模型的返回结果。
And we've got some Output Metadata.
还有一些元数据的输出。
One other thing that we've added here is the ability to add these examples to a data set.
我们在这里添加的另一个功能是
将这些示例添加到数据集中。
So if you remember, when creating those data sets of examples at the start,
如果你还有印象的话，在一开
始创建那些示例数据集时，
we created them partially by hand, partially with a language model.
我们是通过手工和语言模型部分创建的。
Here we can add it to a data set by clicking on this little button,
我们可以通过点击这个小按
钮将其添加到数据集中，
and we now have the input query and the output results.
现在我们有了输入问题和输出结果。
And so we can create a data set.
这样我们就可以创建一个数据集。
And then we can start adding examples to this data set.
然后我们可以开始向这个数据集添加示例。
And so again, getting back to the original thing that we tackled at the beginning of the lesson,
回到我们在课程开始时解决的原始问题，
we need to create these data sets so that we can do evaluation.
我们需要创建这些数据集以便进行评估。
This is a really good way to have this just running in the background
这是一种在后台运行的好方法，
and then add to the example data sets over time and start building up these examples
然后随着时间的推移向示例数据集中
添加内容并开始积累这些示例，
that you can start using for evaluation and have this flywheel of evaluation start turning.
这样你就可以开始将这些数据集用于评
估，并让评估的飞轮开始转动起来。